<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Article, | brick by brick]]></title>
  <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/categories/article/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-25T15:28:48+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://roidriscoll.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Roi Driscoll]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/100-days/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T14:40:22+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/100-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the students at Makers Academy shared <a href="http://www.karenx.com/blog/i-learned-to-dance-in-a-year/">this link</a> with me, and I have to say I really connected with the article (I suspect largely because my best dance moves tend to mimic a reanimated sea bass intent on disproving there is <a href="http://engineering.mit.edu/ask/can-computer-generate-truly-random-number">no such thing as true randomness</a>).</p>

<p>But Irish genes aside, it really got me thinking &ndash; 100 days is pretty cheap in terms of time investment, and it&rsquo;s such a nice round number! I immediately started thinking about the best ways for me to utilise the next hundred days of my calendar&hellip; What could I get my head around by December 3rd 2014? I started thinking about how I had always wanted to move like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zdz88MBWomo">James Brown</a>. But how often am I going to use this skill? Is it going to bring me closer to my current life goals? In software development, we tend to group our features by priority &ndash; and being able to shuffle like a pro, well that&rsquo;s definitely in the &lsquo;Nice to Have&rsquo; pile. For now.</p>

<p>So with that said, I turned my attention immediately to the &lsquo;Must Have&rsquo; column, and oh look at that &ndash; coding was top of the list. Given that my main priority at the moment is to build some seriously sexy dev skills and get an awesome job in industry means that when it comes to goal picking, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ypn9LvsWGsg">there can be only one</a>. So without further ado, I am committed to pushing new code to Github once a day for at least the next 100 days. Joining me on this odyssey is <a href="http://ecomba.pro/">Ecomba</a>, who also intends to make a serious amount of squares green on his profile page. I invite you to get involved, and by the time Christmas comes around you&rsquo;ll have already given yourself an amazing present.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
