<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Article, | brick by brick]]></title>
  <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/categories/article/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-27T00:12:00+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://roidriscoll.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Roi Driscoll]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost Without Crayola]]></title>
    <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/lost-without-crayola/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-26T23:58:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/26/lost-without-crayola</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I come from a creative background. For all the weight that sentence carries, to me the most important meaning is that when left alone to my own devices I am usually able to make something with the tools available.</p>

<p>This is not the result of a carefree and indulgent childhood, but more a richochet of pure stubborness. I did not grow up drawing every evening after school, or taking art classes (I attended art school for a year when I was already working in industry as a Designer). Creativity was always something I was resigned to work at, which was fine. Until I learnt to code.</p>

<p>When you attend an institution like Makers Academy, you don&rsquo;t come out of the other side as a world-class coder. You&rsquo;re not supposed to &ndash; coding is an art form like painting, sculpture or playing the Cello. You only get great by putting the hours in, and paying attention to each little thing you do in those hours. But you do come out with tools. You have the ability to move code into thousands of different shapes, to be able to mould and bend bits and bytes to do your bidding &ndash; even if the elegance and eloquence of experience temporarily eludes you&hellip;</p>

<p>But now I find myself in an odd predicament. I have tools, and no idea how to wield them. Never before have I had such power before my fingertips, and no spark of inspiration with which to apply them &ndash; and it&rsquo;s heart-wrenching. To build for the sake of building &ndash; to play in my text editor&hellip;</p>

<p>As these thoughts haunt me I ask myself why this is so &ndash; and somewhere between now and the next hundred days, I shall bring forth an answer, and share it with you so that you might avoid such frustrations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/100-days/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-25T14:40:22+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://roidriscoll.github.io/blog/2014/08/25/100-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the students at Makers Academy shared <a href="http://www.karenx.com/blog/i-learned-to-dance-in-a-year/">this link</a> with me, and I have to say I really connected with the article (I suspect largely because my best dance moves tend to mimic a reanimated sea bass intent on disproving there is <a href="http://engineering.mit.edu/ask/can-computer-generate-truly-random-number">no such thing as true randomness</a>).</p>

<p>But Irish genes aside, it really got me thinking &ndash; 100 days is pretty cheap in terms of time investment, and it&rsquo;s such a nice round number! I immediately started thinking about the best ways for me to utilise the next hundred days of my calendar&hellip; What could I get my head around by December 3rd 2014? I started thinking about how I had always wanted to move like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zdz88MBWomo">James Brown</a>. But how often am I going to use this skill? Is it going to bring me closer to my current life goals? In software development, we tend to group our features by priority &ndash; and being able to shuffle like a pro, well that&rsquo;s definitely in the &lsquo;Nice to Have&rsquo; pile. For now.</p>

<p>So with that said, I turned my attention immediately to the &lsquo;Must Have&rsquo; column, and oh look at that &ndash; coding was top of the list. Given that my main priority at the moment is to build some seriously sexy dev skills and get an awesome job in industry means that when it comes to goal picking, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ypn9LvsWGsg">there can be only one</a>. So without further ado, I am committed to pushing new code to Github once a day for at least the next 100 days. Joining me on this odyssey is <a href="http://ecomba.pro/">Ecomba</a>, who also intends to make a serious amount of squares green on his profile page. I invite you to get involved, and by the time Christmas comes around you&rsquo;ll have already given yourself an amazing present.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
